<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-04-05T20:39:17+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">James Mathison</title><subtitle>Productivity, copywriting, and the mechanics of spirituality.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Master a Skillset</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/master-a-skillset/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Master a Skillset" /><published>2017-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/master-a-skillset</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/master-a-skillset/">&lt;p&gt;The BEST advice to beginning entrepreneurs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Master a skillset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seems obvious to some, but others will read that and think, “I don’t have time for that (despite being 22).” or, “But you should start with automation/scalability/independence as the goal, right?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to be that kid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fastest way to get to where you really want to go (a successful and fulfilling career), is to &lt;em&gt;master&lt;/em&gt; something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It The MFCEO podcast 126, Mike Dillard seriously &lt;a href=&quot;http://pca.st/3jwF#t=3748&quot;&gt;breaks it down&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“[Mastering a skillset] is the key to everything. If you master a skillset, it empowers you to take action and to get a result and to create momentum in you life. It turns you into a source of value for other individuals.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He goes on to implore: Figure out how your brain is wired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re an analytical, numbers-based person, master Facebook advertising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a more creative type, master copywriting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike is an introverted creative type himself - a type that most would probably say makes a better artist than entrepreneur. He is living proof that self-awareness allows you to manoeuvre around any built-in “limitations”. He hated selling in person, so he learned how to sell with the written word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Entrepreneurship seems to be one of the most personality-agnostic career paths out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter who or what you are, just figure out how to make it work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And master a valuable skillset that falls in line with that.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The BEST advice to beginning entrepreneurs.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22feature%22=%3Enil%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Make Tedious Tasks Easy to Bear</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tedious-tasks/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Make Tedious Tasks Easy to Bear" /><published>2017-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tedious-tasks</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tedious-tasks/">&lt;p&gt;Say you’re a student and have a boring 10-page essay to write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know it’s boring, and you’ve still got a lot to do, but can you bear the boredom &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;right now&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re not currently on the floor, dribbling softly in the fetal position, are you? You are strong enough to handle the sensations of the task in &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;this very moment&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then aren’t you able to bear it indefinitely?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Oh but it’s not just this moment, I’ve got 10 more pages to write!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you writing them in this moment?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No. Those pages, and the idea of writing them, are a simulation in your mind. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The simulation is what hurts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, not the writing of the pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The simulation adds extra suffering to the work at hand. Why are you feeling the pain of writing those pages now, before they are written?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Focus on the page you are on now – no, on the &lt;em&gt;word&lt;/em&gt; you are on now. If that’s bearable, then the whole essay will be bearable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“But those pages still need to be written!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let them wait their turn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“But if I only focus on what I’m currently doing the whole time, then I’ll never know what it feels like to have 10 pages to do.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exactly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll have little moments, of course, of coming up for air. You’ll check how much you have left, and you’ll dive back in, secure in the knowledge that if you can handle writing the next word, you can handle writing the next 5,000. Each one will wait its turn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That’s the good thing about moments. They never gang up on you. They line up in single file and patiently wait their turn.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you can handle one, you can handle them all.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Say you’re a student and have a boring 10-page essay to write.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22feature%22=%3Enil%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Success Question: What Would You Do if You Couldn’t Make Progress?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/if-you-couldnt-progress/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Success Question: What Would You Do if You Couldn't Make Progress?" /><published>2017-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/if-you-couldnt-progress</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/if-you-couldnt-progress/">&lt;p&gt;Of just two skills Tim Ferriss claims are necessary for success, one of those is asking great questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/PnLUpoU714M?start=223&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quote from Peter Thiel that Tim mentions above is laid out in more detail in &lt;em&gt;Tools of Titans&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;If you go back 20 or 25 years, I wish I would have known that there was no need to wait…
So if you're planning to do something with your life, if you have a 10-year plan of how to get there, you should ask: Why can't you do this in 6 months? Sometimes, you have to actually go through the complex, 10-year trajectory. But it's at least worth asking whether that's the story you're telling yourself, or whether that's the reality.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good question is often specific to your situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my situation this year, a good question is the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“What would I do if it was guaranteed that no matter what, I would make no progress at all in the next 6 months?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That question works for me because I am very partial to grandiose fantasies of some big success that’s always just around the corner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I’ve grown older, the time frame has gradually lengthened, but not nearly enough. It takes time to do meaningful things, and my childish labrador-brain refuses to accept it. The “no progress” question forces me into a brief moment of maturity. It reminds me also to spend my time on things I will be happy to do for their own sake, not just as a means to an end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question probably &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be
&lt;em&gt;“What would I do if I were guaranteed to make no progress at all this year?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I find that prospect just a little too terrifying to entertain…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Of just two skills Tim Ferriss claims are necessary for success, one of those is asking great questions.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22feature%22=%3Enil%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Stop Trying To Be Great. Be Great AT Something Instead.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/be-great-at-something/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stop Trying To Be Great. Be Great AT Something Instead." /><published>2017-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/be-great-at-something</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/be-great-at-something/">&lt;p&gt;The Fizzle Show sent out &lt;a href=&quot;https://fizzle.co/sparkline/become-successful-seriously-fs198&quot;&gt;a great episode&lt;/a&gt; this week. It’s a foundational show, asking the question – How do you &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; be successful?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chase sums up an effortlessly profound mental shift at the 44-minute mark:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&quot;Be like Ira Glass. Choose to pursue being great at something, instead of just being great.&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We often fall into the trap of trying to “be great” somehow. Take yourself out of the equation, and the path to greatness becomes a lot simpler and a lot more reachable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Become great at something. Bonus points if it’s something you love.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The Fizzle Show sent out a great episode this week. It’s a foundational show, asking the question – How do you actually be successful?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%7B%22feature%22=%3E%22fizzle-show.jpg%22%7D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How Does One Bridge the Personal &amp;amp; Professional on Social Media?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/personal-vs-professional/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Does One Bridge the Personal &amp; Professional on Social Media?" /><published>2016-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-12-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/personal-vs-professional</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/personal-vs-professional/">&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent today mostly baffled by the amount of content I &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; be putting out into the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I challenged myself with my post on Monday, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.contentlab.io/endless-content-never-run-out-of-ideas-27c60589f98f&quot;&gt;Endless Content&lt;/a&gt; to come up with 40 piece of content, repurposed from that blog post alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was a little much. I only managed 30. But still… &lt;strong&gt;30 pieces of new content&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of it is very simple. Some of it is repetitive, but all of it can be used to promote the blog post itself, so it’s probably a BALL-BREAKING strategy for a business that uses T.O.F.U. (top of funnel) content like blog posts acquire leads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now it’s up to me to put it to the test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The question which haunts me now is…how do I bring my personal and professional profiles together?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I’ve become more content-prolific over the last three weeks, I’ve wanted to keep my Facebook profile at bay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gary Vaynerchuk himself doesn’t mix his Gary V profiles with Vayner Media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’m not sure how to do this. Do I keep Content Lab totally “professional” looking? Or do I throw in some random selfies and talking head monologues and stuff like that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How the hell do you be “social” as a brand? You can publish content, sure, but when I leave comments I want to talk as if it’s me. Then I hit send and it’s the Content Lab logo sending that little sound bite with all that personality…not James.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is of course a thing I’ll need to become familiar with for the good of Content Lab’s clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems I’ve cracked the problem of running out of content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I’m facing the problem of brand vs personal engagement on social media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have no doubt I’ll crack that too.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I’ve spent today mostly baffled by the amount of content I could be putting out into the world.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What You Need to Become Prolific</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/become-prolific/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What You Need to Become Prolific" /><published>2016-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/become-prolific</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/become-prolific/">&lt;p&gt;I’m listening to the MFCEO podcast, and they’re talking about the resistance people feel before making (and publishing) content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I smiled to myself. I used to be that guy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m past it, somehow. It’s worth clarifying how exactly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;whats-different&quot;&gt;What’s Different?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a different perspective. Another attitude. That’s it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-way-i-come-across&quot;&gt;The Way I Come Across&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way I “come across” is no longer a highly valued aspect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the list of things that content production involves, it’s moved down the list. That’s all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;good-enough&quot;&gt;Good Enough&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, the barrier for “good enough” has changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I imagine if someone out there might get something good from it. A moment of reflection, a little smile, or an applicable idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;originality&quot;&gt;Originality&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have no shyness about using someone else’s content to give me fodder for my own. This article itself is a good example. I “steal” from others, and give them props for it. Anyone who didn’t know them is under no illusion that I’m being original, and now they know about the other person or business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Being original” in itself is also low on that list of content priorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, flat originality is impossible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There’s nothing new under the sun. 
– Ecclesiastes, the Bible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Most people are other people. Their thoughts are someone else’s opinions, their lives a mimicry, their passions a quotation.
– Oscar Wilde&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything is an evolution from what came before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, what does “being original” bring to the reader?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High on the list of priorities is giving them something good, remember. It’s the top priority, in fact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make them think, make them smile, or help them progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Being original” does not do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-focus&quot;&gt;The Focus&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The focus is on others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m doing this for my own benefit, but that does not mean it helps to think about myself while I do it. I’m just not really an element of the content I produce. Once it’s out there, the only thing that exists is the interaction between the content and you, the reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not there with you, so why do I matter?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the core of this shift. It’s liberating. It has made me &lt;em&gt;prolific&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it could do the same for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-podcast-clip&quot;&gt;The Podcast Clip:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://overcast.fm/+E0-XS2DZw/1:27:52&quot;&gt;MFCEO 106 - 01:27:52&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You don’t need permission. You don’t have to have someone say, “Oh yes, you’re good on video.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So many people…start off their content with a 20 second whine about how they’re not qualified to do it. Dude, nobody wants to hear that. That’s not content. Skip right to the meat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It makes me as a viewer second-guess myself because I thought I wanted to watch you because you’re smart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I’m listening to the MFCEO podcast, and they’re talking about the resistance people feel before making (and publishing) content.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">One Step to Get Over Social Media Resistance</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/social-media-resistance/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="One Step to Get Over Social Media Resistance" /><published>2016-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/social-media-resistance</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/social-media-resistance/">&lt;p&gt;Trying on different perspectives can change the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found social media like an impenetrable not long ago. Recently, though, I started to see what people like Grant Cardone and Gary Vaynerchuk see in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly the steps I needed to take were obvious. And I took them easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I have accounts for personal and for business, and I’m keeping them updated regularly, keeping top-of-mind with some of my followers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, that just means a few likes and comments from friends. But once I build momentum on the business profiles, it will mean much more than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-attitude-that-kills-social-media-resistance&quot;&gt;The Attitude That Kills Social Media Resistance&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attention is valuable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start watching people around you on the train or in waiting rooms. Where is their attention?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can get close enough to their screens you’ll get more detail. I find it’s either going to be a casual game or a social profile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attention isn’t everything, you also need to bring value to the people giving you attention, but that value can be very simple. Take Kim Kardashian. Just a sexy broad with a superiority complex. Her confidence and looks is both the fuel of her attention and the value her fans get from her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I passed by a Wilbur Smith billboard in the London Underground today. How far into his career did this novelist go before he could afford that much mass attention?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attention is valuable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yesterday, I got the attention of 10s of people by posting a picture of me drawing out some diagrams for my marketing strategy, and another one of my brother’s dog waking up in a cute pose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it. No cost, and I got a bunch of attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m just starting out, just tasting the principles. Those two pictures won’t lead to any money of any kind. However, they did acquire something valuable…attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, that leads to a bigger career, and bigger business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just might need to make future content a little more cohesive!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;resisting-social-media&quot;&gt;Resisting Social Media?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wear someone else’s perspective for a short time. Try it on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attention is valuable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact that today you can earn it &lt;em&gt;at scale&lt;/em&gt; with nothing but a bit of hustle is a thrilling concept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least, it is to those with the right attitude.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Trying on different perspectives can change the game.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Journey to Finding an Endless Source of Motivation (I’m Half-Way There)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/endless-inspiration/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Journey to Finding an Endless Source of Motivation (I'm Half-Way There)" /><published>2016-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/endless-inspiration</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/endless-inspiration/">&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My nose has been on the grindstone since my birthday. I can’t believe that was only 5 days ago!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s felt like twice as long as I’ve poured my brains over Content Lab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A wellspring of &lt;strong&gt;joyful motivation&lt;/strong&gt; has bubbled up from somewhere. It feels so good, I’ve had a few moments of tearing up with joy. I’m getting loads done, and enjoying myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; normal for me, historically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ive-felt-this-way-once-before&quot;&gt;I’ve felt this way once before&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the start of this year I ran out of money. I mean &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; ran out. I calculated I had enough for four kilos of potatoes, and wondering if I could last on that alone for another week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up at 5am every morning. No resistance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I arrived in hub:raum, a local co-working space, before 6:15am most days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked a minimum of 10 hours daily. Once I think I clocked 14 and was shocked at how “fine” I felt. I had been conditioned to fear such long hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It provided a little bit of cranial re-wiring. I not only understood, but &lt;em&gt;experienced&lt;/em&gt; that long hours does not equal unhappiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, as time went on I became happier and happier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time I hit day 7 of eating super-cheap gruel, I felt an occasional burst of exquisite joy and appreciation for life. I tried to share how I was feeling with my friends. It was impossible. It was a bit like I was high, surrounded by sober people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it would seem my advice to anyone who’s dissatisfied with their life is to do the same, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set an income goal, and work like a maniac until you get there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nope. It’s not enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I had money again, I slipped right back into laziness. It took a little while this time, but it felt as unstoppable as the tides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-most-important-part-of-the-motivational-system-is-the-most-misunderstood&quot;&gt;The most important part of the motivational system is the most misunderstood&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fruits were financial stability (and proper meals). The tree trunk was the grind and the hustle. The labour. Most people say if the fruits of your labour suck, you should push harder. Make the trunk better. But that’s not usually going to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trunk is reliant on something else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It needs good roots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the best fruits, everything in the system needs to be on-point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the part of the system found underground (the subconscious), is of course the part many people either ignore or misunderstand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dont-kid-yourself-you-cant-change-it&quot;&gt;Don’t kid yourself. You can’t change it.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least, not by &lt;em&gt;thinking it&lt;/em&gt; into changing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen and heard a lot of self-appointed gurus describe models of the mind that are mostly true. Then they’ll ruin it by making the casual assumption that you can affect the whole thing by changing your thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t kid yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re worried about something, you can’t stop imagining the worst case scenario.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you hate someone, you can’t stop imagining all the ways you’re going to get back at them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe you can stop a few thoughts, but as soon as you move on to another task, up they come again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Your thoughts arise from emotion, not vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sprinkling fertiliser on the leaves of a plant is about as effective as trying to change your soul by forcing your thoughts to be more positive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-only-way-that-works&quot;&gt;The only way that works…&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…is something I’m still working on. ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I know: It requires going deep, and it requires ugliness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It requires &lt;em&gt;facing&lt;/em&gt; things that you would much rather avoid or suppress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It means looking your ugliest feelings and attitudes in the face, and letting them pour over you like a bucket of black slime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s suffocating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I once “caught” a rising sensation of anxiety that came from seemingly nowhere. I was able to coax it to the surface, where I held it by the throat and forced myself to feel it as much as I could.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Although I use the word “forced”, it actually felt more like a process of acceptance).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I became short of breath.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hyperventilated for minutes on end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Energy drained out of my muscles and I slunk to the floor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The terrible wastefulness of my daily choices of lazy self-sabotage became &lt;em&gt;painfully&lt;/em&gt; clear, and I begged forgiveness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;. . .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When my energy returned, I started to laugh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt exquisite relief, and a cloud-9 joy that lasted for about half an hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve had a few experiences like that recently. They’ve been possible because I have stopped trying to mentally analyse my way out of my behavioural issues, and instead I’ve learned to connect with and let go of emotion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-other-factors&quot;&gt;The other factors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t say with total certainty that my inner emotional work is solely to thank for this recent burst in energy, bravery, and inspiration…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…but I have plenty of food this time, so what else could it be? ;-D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be fair, I have just moved back to my home country, and the change in environment may have helped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was also engaged in work that didn’t engage me back, a few months ago. Now I have a big mission that I’m pushing towards. That could be contributing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But again, are those not just the fruits?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My choices to move out of a comfortable location and to take the risk of pursuing Content Lab are the &lt;strong&gt;effects&lt;/strong&gt; of the internal changes I’ve been putting myself through this year. They’re not &lt;strong&gt;causes&lt;/strong&gt; of the change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;should-i-be-telling-this-story&quot;&gt;Should I be telling this story?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s pretty personal, I know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m just shocked that so few people are talking about aspect of human nature. I know I’m not the only one who’s discovered it, because I discovered it from someone else!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope it’s not unknown because it’s unmarketable. For sure it’s easier to sell seats to a seminar that promises to show you the 10 minute exercise that will reverse your limiting beliefs once and for all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compare that with…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Roll up and we’ll force you to face your worst internal horrors and help you heal them through acceptance and forgiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yeah…that’s a harder sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it’s what works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/____?start=____&amp;end=____&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
--&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"> </summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Pain of The ONE Thing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/pain-of-the-one-thing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Pain of The ONE Thing" /><published>2016-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/pain-of-the-one-thing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/pain-of-the-one-thing/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@jsmathison/the-pain-of-the-one-thing-b8e1b75590ca&quot;&gt;Click here to read this article on Medium (when it’s published there).&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quarter of an hour ago I planned out 1h 30m of time to focus on Content Lab’s next ONE Thing that could make everything else easier or irrelevant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Straight away the begrudging answer was, “Hire a writer already”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then into my head swept all the things I have to do – no, all the things I &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; like I have to do - to make Content Lab “ready” for the first client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stopped the time at 13 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I now want to go into overdrive to do all those things &lt;em&gt;myself&lt;/em&gt;, even though I just said to myself that a writer would make a lot of these tasks irrelevant for me to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know it’s holding me back, but I want to do it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of the old self-sabotage creeping in I suppose. Still, a form of self-sabotage that has you write a blog post when you feel like procrastinating is a pretty good one. I’ll take it over alcoholism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-content-lab-really-needs-might-not-be-content&quot;&gt;What Content Lab Really Needs Might Not Be Content&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have it lodged in my head that Content Lab needs a following on Medium, Instagram, and all the other biggies before I can think about charging anyone money to do it for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see the noble place that comes from…I want to be integrous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there are other ways to be integrous without slowing my progress to a crawl. For example, I could offer money back guarantees if certain goals are not met for my first client. Or offer to do it for at-cost pricing. That way, I can build up their following while building up my own, as well as gaining a testimonial and a referral or two out of this first client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know all this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I’m not going to do it…yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just one more blog post, then I’ll quit. I swear!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="success" /><category term="focus" /><summary type="html">Click here to read this article on Medium (when it’s published there).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Start with the ideal</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/start-with-the-ideal/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Start with the ideal" /><published>2016-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/start-with-the-ideal</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/start-with-the-ideal/">&lt;p&gt;Then work backwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to run an ideal startup? an ideal team? write an ideal book? life the ideal life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start with the ideal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Derek Sivers, in his book &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Anything-You-Want-Lessons-Entrepreneur/dp/0241209048/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Anything You Want&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, in the chapter titled “Make a Dream Come True”, describes how he started CD Baby this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s fascinating. He built such an awesome company because he started it by trying to design something that would &lt;em&gt;stay small!&lt;/em&gt; He was already living his dream life as a full-time musician, and he didn’t want anything to distract him from that. But CD Baby was online already and helping some of his friends, plus some of theirs and some of theirs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I thought that by taking an unrealistically utopian approach, I could keep the business from growing too big.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His mind was free from all the trappings of ambition. Without any desire to grow big, why not just make it as perfect for the customers as possible?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I wrote down my utopian dream-come-true distribution deal from my musicians’ point of view.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;‘In an ideal world, my distributor would:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Pay me every week.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Show me the full name and address of everyone who bought my CD.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Never kick me out for not selling enough.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Never allow paid placement.’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And that’s it! That was my mission. I liked it. It was a worthy hobby.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Man…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine if more business were started out with that frame of mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A worthy hobby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Built with the sole purpose of helping some group of people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###It you want to build a startup, begin with this process:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Put yourself deep into the minds of the people you would serve.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ask yourself, “In a perfect world…”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Write down what comes to mind, and keep it brief.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve just written your mission statement. If it doesn’t get you excited, if it doesn’t feel like a &lt;em&gt;worthy and challenging hobby&lt;/em&gt;, then reconsider if you really want to be doing this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And why not take it further?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re considering spending time on &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt;, from getting in shape to taking up an instrument, start with the ideal. The perfect utopia. Try to let go of the desire to attain anything. Think of it like a hobby that’s worthy of your time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Then work backwards.</summary></entry></feed>